Yue Wang

Montreal, Canada wangyuehi@gmail.com

in wangyuehi

wangyuehi.github.io

Summary

3D programmer at Ubisoft Montreal. 7 years experience in graphic programming, mainly focusing on real-time rendering, physically based rendering, raytracing and global illumination.

Skills

LANGUAGES C++, GLSL, HLSL, Python, MATLAB, Mathematica, LaTeX

GRAPHIC APIS DirectX 12, Vulkan, PS4 GNM, PS5 AGC, PSR, DXR

PIX (PC/Xbox), RenderDoc, NSight, PS4/PS5 SCUI, PS4/PS5 Razor Tools Git, Perforce, Mathematica, Houdini, MeshLab, Blender, Photoshop

Work Experience

OCT 2021 -	- PRESENT
------------	-----------

3D Programmer at Anvil Engine/Assassin's Creed, Ubisoft Montreal

- Led a small team developing raytracing global illumination (GI) and related systems
- Supported production GI features in Anvil Engine on PC, PS5 and Xbox Series X/S • Implemented state-of-the-art sampling strategies for improving GI convergence
- Optimized raytracing shaders for better performance based on platform constraints

JAN 2021 - OCT. 2021

3D Programmer at Anvil Engine, Ubisoft Montreal

- Worked on ray-traced dynamic GI solution in Anvil Engine
- Supported raytracing BVH management for static and dynamic meshes
- Implemented automatic raytracing material approximation and management
- Worked on raytracing API abstraction for multiple platforms

JAN 2019 - DEC 2020

3D Programmer at Assassin's Creed Valhalla, Ubisoft Montreal

- Developed deep snow (terrain deformation) and deferred snow system
- · Maintained and improved the weather system (rain, storm, cloud) in collaboration with artists
- Debugged engine and graphic issues, profiled and optimized shaders on PC, PS4, PS5, and Xbox

JUNE 2018 - DEC 2018

3D Programmer Intern at LA FORGE, UBISOFT MONTREAL

- Implemented system to place cubemaps non-uniformly given static 3D scenes
- Optimized probe-space ray-marcher for accurate reflections at runtime

JULY 2017 - MAR 2018

3D Programmer Intern at LA FORGE, UBISOFT MONTREAL

- Implemented light-field probe algorithm and fully integrated into Anvil engine
- Tested and profiled in Rainbow Six on PC and PS4 for improving specular reflections

SUMMER 2015

Programmer Intern at RTX LAB, UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA, Edmonton

- Implemented FPGA-based 2D Finite Element Method(FEM) for motor simulations
- Optimized the sparse solver for the system of linear equations of FEM

PUBLICATIONS

May 2019

Fast Non-uniform Radiance Probe Placement and Tracing

- · ACM SIGGRAPH Symposium on Interactive 3D Graphics and Games 2019, Montreal, Canada
- Best Student Presentation Award

OCT 2015

StreamVisND: Visualizing relationships in streaming multivariate data

- IEEE Symposium on Visual Analytics Science and Technology 2015, Chicago, USA
- VAST Honorable Mention Poster

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Thesis), Computer Science, McGill University Sep 2016 - Dec 2018 SEP 2012 - JUNE 2016 Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Shandong University